[
 {
  "id": "c9bueg5vqc7k2t7cpeb0",
  "question": "Explain the context switching done by an operating system",
  "answer": "Context switching is the act of moving the processor (CPU) between different processes. Context switching is done by saving the state of the current process, and making the CPU process another program. This way a single CPU can run multiple processes at once.",
  "tag": "Computer Systems",
  "goal": 5,
  "completed": 0,
  "tries": 0,
  "successrate": 0
 },
 {
  "id": "c9bugj5vqc7k4fdp56v0",
  "question": "Explain the memory hierarchy and why it is important.",
  "answer": "The memory hierarchy is the organizational structure of storage devices in a computer system. At the top of the memory hierarchy is the register, the component of the CPU that stores the information about the next process that is going to be run. The register is by far the fastest and smallest storage device on a computer system. At the bottom is the remote secondary storage (web storage etc.) which is the slowest to access but also the one that might be the largest. Just on top of this is the local secondary storage (local disks). It is important to know about the memory hierarchy as most of the time spent running programs is on copying information from different locations in the system. Thus, if we can optimize our programs to minimize or increase the speed of this we imigth achieve an order of magnitude increased performance.",
  "tag": "Computer Systems",
  "goal": 5,
  "completed": 0,
  "tries": 0,
  "successrate": 0
 },
 {
  "id": "c9buhp5vqc7k5tad02dg",
  "question": "What are the two tasks of the operating system?",
  "answer": "The first task is to protect the hardware from misuse. The second is to provide applications with simple and uniform mechanisms for manipulating complicated and often wildly different low-level hardware devices.",
  "tag": "Computer Systems",
  "goal": 5,
  "completed": 0,
  "tries": 0,
  "successrate": 0
 },
 {
  "id": "c9buifdvqc7k6c8t615g",
  "question": "What are the fundamental abstractions of the operating system?",
  "answer": "The first is files, which are abstractions for I/O devices. The second is virtual memory, which is an abstraction for program memory, including both main memory and I/O devices. The third is processes, which are abstractions for the running program, including main memory, I/O devices and the processor.",
  "tag": "Computer Systems",
  "goal": 5,
  "completed": 0,
  "tries": 0,
  "successrate": 0
 },
 {
  "id": "c9bukjdvqc7k7enpcu5g",
  "question": "What is an operating system kernel and where does it reside?",
  "answer": "The operating system kernel is a collection of code and data structures that the system uses to manage all the processes. The kernel part of the operating system always resides in the main memory, ready to be used.",
  "tag": "Computer Systems",
  "goal": 5,
  "completed": 0,
  "tries": 0,
  "successrate": 0
 },
 {
  "id": "c9busmdvqc7k9dc1mhn0",
  "question": "What is virtual memory and what are its components?",
  "answer": "Virtual memory is an abstraction that provides each process with the illusion that it has exclusive use of the main memory. Each process has the same uniform view of memory, known as its virtual address space. The virtual address space is split into five locations: 1) Code and data, begins at the same fixed address and is fixed in length after initialization of the program, 2) Heap,, controlled by malloc and free in C and can expand and contract in size, 3) Shared libraries, such as the C standard library and the math library, 4) Stack, dynamically sized memory for function calls, expands when a function is called and c contracts when the function is returned, 5) Kernel virtual memory, the virtual address space for the kernel.",
  "tag": "Computer Systems",
  "goal": 5,
  "completed": 0,
  "tries": 0,
  "successrate": 0
 },
 {
  "id": "c9c0r3lvqc7kni9rrh5g",
  "question": "Give a definition of Amdahl's Law.",
  "answer": "Amdahl's law states that the effect of an increase in onperformance in one part of a programs is determined by the size of the increase in performance and the significance of the part of the program on the whole program. Thus, a component that originally took (alpha * T_old), takes (alpha * T_old)/k after thee increase, where alpha is the significance and k is the performance increase. The overall increase in program performance can eb computed as S = 1 / ((1 - alpha) + alpha / k). The eoverall effect of the performance increase in one part of the system is thus smaller than the effect on the individual part.",
  "tag": "Computer Systems",
  "goal": 5,
  "completed": 0,
  "tries": 0,
  "successrate": 0
 },
 {
  "id": "c9c0srtvqc7kolbdnb00",
  "question": "Describe concurrency and parallelism in simple terms.",
  "answer": "Concurrency refer to the general concept of a system with multiple, simultaneous activities. Parallelism refers to the use of concurrency to make a system run faster.",
  "tag": "Computer Systems",
  "goal": 5,
  "completed": 0,
  "tries": 0,
  "successrate": 0
 },
 {
  "id": "c9c2bf5vqc7l3pjbm6rg",
  "question": "What is a pointer and how might it differ between machines?",
  "answer": "A pointer is an virtual address in the virtual address space. Pointers are the way the computer knows where to look for data or instructions when running computations. Pointers also include what type the data is at the location. The pointer can differ between machines if there are differences in the word size. The word size is the nominal size of pointer data. A 32-bit machine has a word size of 32-bits and a 64-bit machine has a word size of 64 bits. Most modern computers use the 64-bit word size, as it allows the virtual address space to scale up to 16 exabytes, whereas the 32-bit word size only allows 4 gigabytes.",
  "tag": "Computer Systems",
  "goal": 5,
  "completed": 0,
  "tries": 0,
  "successrate": 0
 },
 {
  "id": "c9c2g7lvqc7l5l0ujdf0",
  "question": "Explain little-endian and big-endian?",
  "answer": "The endians are ways of sorting the bytes representing program object. Little-endian is the convention where the least significant bytes comes first and big-endian is the convention where the most significant byte comes first. There are no benefits of choosing one over the other. Most Intel-compatible machines operate exclusively on little-endian, while most machines from IBM and Oracle operate in big-endian mode. Many recent micro-processor chips are bi-endian. However, byteordering becomes fixed once a particular operating system is chosen.",
  "tag": "Computer Systems",
  "goal": 5,
  "completed": 0,
  "tries": 0,
  "successrate": 0
 },
 {
  "id": "c9c2hrtvqc7l6kh1fovg",
  "question": "In which applications can byteordering become an issue?",
  "answer": "When binary data are communicated over a network between different machines. A common problem is for data produced by a little-endian machine to be sent to a big-endian machine, or vice versa, leading to the bytes within the words being in reverse for the receiving program. To avoid such problems, code written for network applications must follow established conventions for byteordering. A second case where byteordering becomes important is when looking at the byte sequences representing iteger data. This occurs when inspecting machine-level programs. A third case where byteordering become visible is when programs are written that circumvent the normal type system. In the C language, this can be done using a cast or a union to allow an object to be referenced according to a different data type from which it was created. Such tricks are strongly discouraged for most application programming, but they can be quite useful and even necessary for system-level programming.",
  "tag": "Computer Systems",
  "goal": 5,
  "completed": 0,
  "tries": 0,
  "successrate": 0
 },
 {
  "id": "c9d6tj5vqc7jv7gckcb0",
  "question": "Explain a stack in the context of x64 Assembly.",
  "answer": "A stack is a data structure where values can be added or deleted, but only according to the last-in, first-out discipline. We add data to a stack via a push operation and remove it via a pop operation, with the property that the value popped will always be the value that was most recently pushed on the stack. A stack can be implemented as an array, where we always insert and remove elements from one end of the array. This end is called the top of the stack. With x86-64, the program stack is stored in some region of memory. The stack grows downward such that the top element of the stack has the lowest address of all stack elements. The stack pointer %rsp holds the address of the top stack element. The pushq instruction provides the ability to push data onto the stack, while the popq instruction pops it.",
  "tag": "Computer Systems",
  "goal": 5,
  "completed": 0,
  "tries": 0,
  "successrate": 0
 },
 {
  "id": "c9da7n5vqc7l8u5k3b1g",
  "question": "What are constants in golang?",
  "answer": "A constant in golang declares a constant value. A const statement can appear anywhere a var statement can. Constant expressions perform arithmetic with arbitrary precision. A numeric constant has no type until it is given one, such as by explicit conversion.",
  "tag": "Go",
  "goal": 5,
  "completed": 0,
  "tries": 0,
  "successrate": 0
 },
 {
  "id": "c9del51sluv26qhf1m80",
  "question": "What is a multiplexor?",
  "answer": "A multiplexor is a three-input gate that uses one of the inputs, called the selection bit, to select and output one of the other two inputs, called data bits. If the selector is 0 it returns the first data bit, if the selector is 1, it returns the second data bit.",
  "tag": "Computer Systems",
  "goal": 5,
  "completed": 0,
  "tries": 0,
  "successrate": 0
 },
 {
  "id": "c9deln1sluv3rf822ak0",
  "question": "What is a Demultiplexor?",
  "answer": "A demultiplexor performs the opposite function of the multiplexor: it takes a single input and channels it to one of two possible outputs, according to a selector bit that specifies which output to choose.",
  "tag": "Computing Systems",
  "goal": 5,
  "completed": 0,
  "tries": 0,
  "successrate": 0
 }
]